# Henry Sloan van Wagenberg - Software Developer

http://baugarten.io Dudenstraße 32a Kreuzberg, Berlin 10965

https://github.com/Henryvw RMSAHenry {Skype} henryvw@gmail.com

# Programming Experience Summary

I am a self-taught programmer & freelancer with 5 years experience working mostly on the backend side of Ruby projects, mostly, but not only, in the context of Rails, for startups in Berlin including Blacklane, FinLeap, Movinga and Helpling among others. I've also had a small amount of experience working with Javascript and Node applications and AWS and related DevOps technologies. 5 years experience with Git. \*\*VIM user\*\*



#### **About Me**

I've cut broccoli on a Danish farm, co-founded and sold one start-up, RateMyStudyAbroad.com, project-managed a development team in the Philippines (while living there on-site), studied philosophy for one year while living in a cottage, sailed across the Pacific Ocean, practiced business sales in New York and interned at the White House. I love programming, solving problems, and taking risks.

# Employment Experience - Programming

**Co-Founder** baugarten.io, 2016 - present Software Developer & General-Purpose Problem-Solver I work together with other developers as little freelancing teams to build applications and to support start-ups.

### **Blacklane GmbH**, 2014 - 2016

Ruby Developer

I worked on the Ruby on Rails applications which support the customerfacing <u>blacklane.com</u>.

# SmartLogic.io GmbH, 2014

Managing Director, Berlin Office

Led foundation of the Berlin office of US-based, Ruby-on-Rails application-building SmartLogic. SmartLogic supports startups with external development teams and consulting focusing on Ruby on Rails.

## White Cheetah - Crowd911, 2013

Junior Ruby on Rails Developer

Junior Rails developer for Colorado-based Crowd911, an enterprise solution for emergency alert management. Participated in daily standups, sprint planning process and agile workflow using Pivotal Tracker, git and Github. Paired with developers on the following using RSpec TDD: creating alert message actions via Rails Controller, customizing Active Admin, customizing JSON outputs to our mobile dev team, using Rails models to structure our database for alert severity and many-to-many table relationships between crowds and alerts. Mentored by a Hewlett-Packard developer. Selected as "tech guy" to represent the product at 2013 San Francisco TechCrunch Disrupt.

Employment
Experience Outside of
Programming

### RateMyStudyAbroad.com, 2010 - 2013

Co-Founder and Director

Founded, raised funds, managed developers and designers, and led sales to create independent study abroad site with 5,000+ student reviews. Forged strategic partnership and ~\$200k investment with GoAbroad.com, the largest abroad directory in the world 2011- 13. Moved to GoAbroad's Philippines office for 7 months. Managed team of 7 Filipino PHP Symfony developers and project-managed two large software projects. Managed 3 sales interns in Colorado HQ. Drove a bus across North America to sell review software product to universities. Small successful exit for \$70k + 2.5 year salary. GoAbroad acquired 100% of RateMyStudyAbroad in 2013. Customer interviews - <a href="http://tinyurl.com/qa2vfr9">http://tinyurl.com/qa2vfr9</a>

## Philosophy Year, 2009 - 2010

Self-Study Project

I committed one year of my life to studying Greek and Roman philosophy, beginning with the Pre-Socratics, Plato and Aristotle. Waited tables and bartender in the evening to fund my self-study project

#### Mimeo.com, 2008 - 2009

Account Executive

80 phone calls per day articulating and selling New York, NY based Mimeo.com's online print and logistics solution

# Presidential Personnel, The White House, 2007

Intern

Took phone calls, escorted candidates, prepared resume summary documents, attended West Wing staff meetings. Presidential Personnel advises the president on cabinet and other senior staff personnel decisions

# Democratic Progressive Party (DPP), Taipei, Taiwan, 2005

Intern, International Department

Overhauled and reformatted English newsletter for governing party of the Republic of China. Assisted with visits from foreign press, representatives and scholars

### Gyldensteen Estates, Bogense, Denmark, 2002

Broccoli Cutter

Cut broccoli in broccoli fields. Gyldensteen is one of the largest agricultural producers in Denmark

#### **Education**

# **BA English Literature, Minor Economics, 2007**

Davidson College, North Carolina, GPA 3.33

**Tall Ship Sailor/Deckhand & Oceanography Student**, 2007 USS *Robert Seamans*, Sea Education Association, Woods Hole, Massachussets

# German Language Immersion & Semester Study Abroad, 2005

Universität Würzburg, Würzburg, Germany

### Intensive 1st year Mandarin Chinese, 2004

Middlebury College, Vermont

#### **Volunteer Work**

#### Die Lernwerkstatt e.V., 2015 - 2017

I co-founded a German non-profit which hosts a variety of learning programs. I teach a 1-day workshop on introductory programming to people of all ages. (In German and in English). We build a small Ruby "to-do list" application using Sinatra.

#### RailsGirls Coach, 2014-15

Coached at workshops hosted by the Berlin-chapter of the organization, which teaches women learning programming. Two women I coached went on to get full time jobs as developers.

# StoicPenknife.com, 2014-17

In my spare time I created a free, open-source application to practice the ancient Greek & Roman Stoic philosophical "technologies of the soul". I released it in March, 2017 and it is used by a small number of people around the world by interested in Stoic philosophy and ancient philosophy as a form of "philosophical therapy".

e-signature: Henry van Wagenberg 22. January 2019